Guide to the Morocco Collection
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Morocco collection
1867-1991
1920-1991
MS 1532
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
0.75
The collection consists of printed material relating to political and social conditions in Morocco and photographs.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Transferred from the African Collection Curator.
Associated Materials
African Collection, MS 605; African Postcard Collection, MS 1575; Pamphlet Collection, MS 1351. Manuscripts and Archives, Yale University Library.
Arrangement
The material in the original accession is arranged chronologically, with photographs last. Additions to the collection may vary in arrangement.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of printed material relating to political and social conditions in Morocco and photographs.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Morocco -- Description and travel; Morocco -- Politics and government; Morocco -- Social conditions; Photographs -- Morocco
- Inventory
  - Journals: cultural and academic, 1978-1991 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Government documents; journals; reports, 1979-1984 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Political organizations: bulletins; journals; printed material, 1979-1984 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Newspapers: general, 1980-1991 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Institute of Current World Affairs: newsletters, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - "La Guerra del Rif": numbers 1-16, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Photograph album of scenes from Morocco, [1920?-1930?] (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Album containing postcards; general information pamphlets; brochures; booklets; maps, [1958?] (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Additional Material, Accession 1997-M-007
  - Amnesty International flyer on the disappearance of Ahmed Lemaadal El Bou, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - "Order Of Her Majesty In Council For The Regulation Of Consular Jurisdiction In The Dominions Of The Sultan Of Morocco. Osborne House, 27th August, 1857", 1867 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - "Tangier," produced by the Official Tourist Office, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - U.S. policy on arms for Morocco [articles from various organizations], 1979-1982, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - La Voix du Maroc [newspaper], 1946 January 23 (Box 1, Folder 5)